# Jahid Hassan

Dhaka, Bangladesh

(880) 181-445-0361 | jahid.hassan.ce@gmail.com | mjhassan.github.io

# Summary

Highly self-motivated and team lead experienced with 9 years building iOS application, includes requirement analysis, architecting, software design, coding, testing and maintaining under agile environment. Experienced on maintaining, converting and enhancing existing codebase. Well versed in TDD, BDD, HIG, Instruments, CI/CD and different design patterns. Having experience in developing hybrid applications in React Native and Xamarin.

# Skills (fluent, proficient, familiar)

- **Swift**, Objective C, React Native, Xamarin, *Kotlin*, *Java*, *python*, *C*, *C*++, *HTML*, *CSS*, *Shell*, *Groovy*
- **UIKit**, **MapKit**, **UIStoryboard**, **AutoLayout**, **CoreGraphics**, Xib, GCD, CoreAnimation, ARKit, RxSwift, XCTest, APNS, Express.js, Node.js, *Electron.js*, *Vapor*, *Perfect*, *Quick and Nimble*, *JUnit*, *Mockito*, *NUnit*, *Moq*
- CoreData, SQLite, Realm, AWS, Firebase, MongoDB, MySQL, MSSQL
- TDD, MVVM, MVC, Agile (Scrum, Kanban), BDD, MVP, MVVM-C, VIPER
- Cocoapods, Git, Carthage, SVN, Package Manager
- **Xcode, VSCode,** Android Studio, Instruments, Application Loader, Github, Bitbucket, GitLab, Jenkins, fastlane, Jira, Trello, AppStore Management, TestFlight, MS AppCenter, GooglePlay, *Eclipse*, *AppCoda, Postman, Sketch, Balsamiq, InVision, Figma*
- UI/UX, performance tuning and optimization, Team management and guiding

### Certifications

• Certified ScrumMaster® (CSM®)

### Experience

### Infolytx, Bangladesh

### Staff Software Engineer, Apr 2019 - Present

- Develop engineering system required documents along with design mobile software.
- Take part in the development process.
- Present consistently accurate as well as timely software.
- Report on entire project achievement and issues.
- Take ownership of the solution from end to end, and be responsible for translating functional requirements into a mobile solution

#### **Technical Lead, Feb 2016 - Mar 2019**

- Led and monitored the mobile team in an agile environment
- Took part in the development process
- Defined the technical requirements for the implementation of the mobile solution.
- Took ownership of the solution from end to end, and was responsible for translating functional requirements into a mobile solution
- Researched and did development on cutting-edge technologies to extend scope.

#### **Brain Station-23, Bangladesh**

#### Senior Software Engineer, Feb 2015 – Jan 2016

- Provided B2B service as a remote iOS developer to Aareas Interactive, Canada
- Translated requirements and mock-ups into fully functioning features
- Designed and built applications for the iOS platform
- Ensured the performance, quality, and responsiveness of applications
- Collaborated with a team to define, design, and ship new features
- Identified and correct bottlenecks and fix bugs
- Helped maintain code quality, organization, and automatization.

#### Software Engineer, Feb 2013 - Jan 2015

- Provided B2B service as a remote iOS developer to Aareas Interactive, Canada
- Provided estimates on development cycles
- Implemented of new module as per client's requirements.
- Identified and fixed bugs on existing projects.
- Refactored existing projects and improved app performance.
- Updated UI and ensure code quality.

#### **Nydtech Solutions, Bangladesh**

#### iOS Developer, May 2012 - Jan 2013

- Identified and fixed bugs on existing projects.
- Refactored existing projects and improved app performance.
- Updated UI and ensure code quality.
- Designed and implemented of puzzle, trivia type games for the iOS platform.

### Metafour, Bangladesh

### Software Developer, May 2011 - Dec 2012

- Fixed bugs and improve application performance.
- Monitored and maintained application for Tucan Travel on daily basis.

# Education

Shahjalal University of Science and Technology (SUST), Sylhet, Bangladesh B.Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering (2005-2009), 3.74

### **Publications**

- To NSCache or not to NSCache, what is the URLCache (2019) at medium.com
- Generate a signed APK from React Native project (2018) at medium.com
- Vapor: Server Side Swift Noob's Guide. Infolytx blog.